<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<root version="3.0" release="1|3.5E:14|CoreRPG:3">
	<library static="true">
		<BRP_Classes>
			<name type="string">PFRPG Misc Classes</name>
			<categoryname type="string">Black Rose Pathfinder</categoryname>
			<entries>
				<aegis>
					<librarylink type="windowreference">
						<class>referenceindex</class>
						<recordname>lists.aegis.basemenu@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
					</librarylink>
					<name type="string">Aegis</name>
				</aegis>
				<artifacer>
					<librarylink type="windowreference">
						<class>referenceindex</class>
						<recordname>lists.artifacer.basemenu@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
					</librarylink>
					<name type="string">Artifacer</name>
				</artifacer>
				<cryptic>
					<librarylink type="windowreference">
						<class>referenceindex</class>
						<recordname>lists.cryptic.basemenu@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
					</librarylink>
					<name type="string">cryptic</name>
				</cryptic>
				<tactician>
					<librarylink type="windowreference">
						<class>referenceindex</class>
						<recordname>lists.tactician.basemenu@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
					</librarylink>
					<name type="string">Tactician</name>
				</tactician>
				<vitalists>
					<librarylink type="windowreference">
						<class>referenceindex</class>
						<recordname>lists.vitalists.basemenu@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
					</librarylink>
					<name type="string">Vitalists</name>
				</vitalists>
			</entries>
		</BRP_Classes>
	</library>
	
	<reference static="true">
		<proficiencies>
				<lightarmor>
					<name type="string">Light</name>
					<type type="string">Combat</type>
					<mult type="number">0</mult>
					<stack type="number">0</stack>
					<benefit type="formattedtext">
						<p>You are skilled at wearing light armors. When you wear light armor, the armor check penalty for that armor applies only to Dexterity- and Strength-based skill checks.</p>
					</benefit>
					<normal type="formattedtext">
						<p>A character who is wearing armor with which he is not proficient applies its armor check penalty to attack rolls and to all skill checks that involve moving.</p>
					</normal>
				</lightarmor>
				<mediumarmor>
					<name type="string">Medium</name>
					<type type="string">Combat</type>
					<mult type="number">0</mult>
					<stack type="number">0</stack>
					<prerequisites type="string">
						Light Armor Proficiency.
					</prerequisites>
					<benefit type="formattedtext">
						<p>You are skilled at wearing medium armor. When you wear medium armor, the armor check penalty for that armor applies only to Dexterity- and Strength-based skill checks.</p>
					</benefit>
					<normal type="formattedtext">
						<p>A character who is wearing armor with which he is not proficient applies its armor check penalty to attack rolls and to all skill checks that involve moving.</p>
					</normal>
				</mediumarmor>
				<heavyarmor>
					<name type="string">Heavy</name>
					<type type="string">Combat</type>
					<mult type="number">0</mult>
					<stack type="number">0</stack>
					<prerequisites type="string">
						Light Armor Proficiency, Medium Armor Proficiency.
					</prerequisites>
					<benefit type="formattedtext">
						<p>You are skilled at wearing heavy armor. When you wear heavy armor, the armor check penalty for that armor applies only to Dexterity- and Strength-based skill checks.</p>
					</benefit>
					<normal type="formattedtext">
						<p>A character who is wearing armor with which he is not proficient applies its armor check penalty to attack rolls and to all skill checks that involve moving.</p>
					</normal>
				</heavyarmor>
				<regularshields>
					<name type="string">Shield</name>
					<type type="string">Combat</type>
					<mult type="number">0</mult>
					<stack type="number">0</stack>
					<benefit type="formattedtext">
						<p>You are trained in how to properly use a shield. When you use a shield (except a tower shield), the shield's armor check penalty only applies to Strength- and Dexterity-based skills.</p>
					</benefit>
					<normal type="formattedtext">
						<p>When you are using a shield with which you are not proficient, you take the shield's armor check penalty on attack rolls and on all skill checks that involve moving.</p>
					</normal>
				</regularshields>
				<towershields>
					<name type="string">Tower Shield</name>
					<type type="string">Combat</type>
					<mult type="number">0</mult>
					<stack type="number">0</stack>
					<prerequisites type="string">
						Shield Proficiency.
					</prerequisites>
					<benefit type="formattedtext">
						<p>You are trained in how to properly use a tower shield. When you use a tower shield, the shield's armor check penalty only applies to Strength and Dexterity-based skills.</p>
					</benefit>
					<normal type="formattedtext">
						<p>A character using a shield with which he is not proficient takes the shield's armor check penalty on attack rolls and on all skill checks that involve moving, including Ride.</p>
					</normal>
				</towershields>
				<simpleweapons>
					<name type="string">Simple</name>
					<type type="string">Combat</type>
					<mult type="number">0</mult>
					<stack type="number">0</stack>
					<benefit type="formattedtext">
						<p>You are trained in the use of basic weapons. You make attack rolls with simple weapons without penalty.</p>
					</benefit>
					<normal type="formattedtext">
						<p>When using a weapon with which you are not proficient, you take a –4 penalty on attack rolls.</p>
					</normal>
				</simpleweapons>
				<martialweapons>
					<name type="string">Martial</name>
					<type type="string">Combat</type>
					<mult type="number">0</mult>
					<stack type="number">0</stack>
					<benefit type="formattedtext">
						<p>You understand how to use one or more martial weapons in combat. You make attack rolls with all or one selected martial weapon normally.</p>
					</benefit>
					<normal type="formattedtext">
						<p>When using a weapon with which you are not proficient, you take a –4 penalty on attack rolls.</p>
					</normal>
				</martialweapons>
				<favoredweapon>
					<name type="string">Favored Weapon []</name>
					<type type="string">Class</type>
					<mult type="number">0</mult>
					<stack type="number">0</stack>
					<benefit type="formattedtext">
						<p>You are proficient with the favored weapon of your deity.</p>
					</benefit>
					<normal type="formattedtext">
						<p>A character who uses a weapon with which he is not proficient takes a –4 penalty on attack rolls.</p>
					</normal>
				</favoredweapon>
		</proficiencies>
		<aegis>
			<astralrepair>
				<name type="string">Astral Repair (Ps)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>An aegis is capable of repairing mundane items, restoring 2 hit points of damage to the touched item as a standard action usable at will.</p>
					<p>If the object has the broken condition, this condition is removed if the object is restored to at least half its original hit points.</p>
					<p>All of the pieces of an object must be present for this ability to function. This ability has no effect on objects that have been warped</p>
					<p>or otherwise transmuted, but it can still repair damage done to such items.</p>
				</benefit>
			</astralrepair>
			<formastralsuit>
				<name type="string">Form Astral Suit (Su)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>Every aegis learns to draw forth ectoplasm and form an astral suit around their form.</p>
					<p>The aegis can select from three different types when forming his astral suit- skin, armor, or juggernaut.</p>
					<p>An aegis is always considered to be proficient with his astral suit, even if he does not have the appropriate armor proficiency.</p>
					<p>The amount of time forming this astral suit takes depends on the type of suit being formed.</p>
					<p>Different astral suit forms grant different free customizations.</p>
					<p>These free customizations never count against the aegis's total number of customization points spent on his astral suit.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>The aegis chooses the appearance of his astral suit, although its shape must reflect the selections the aegis has chosen:</p>
					<p>astral skin would cover the aegis like a psychoactive skin, astral juggernaut would appear to cover the aegis like plate armor, etc.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>An astral suit can be dismissed as a free action.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>An astral suit does not function in areas where psionics do not work, such as a null psionics field.</p>
					<p>Dismiss ectoplasm can be used against an astral suit; treat the manifester level as the aegis's class level,</p>
					<p>although the aegis can simply form his astral suit again on his next turn.</p>
				</benefit>
			</formastralsuit>
			<craftsman>
				<name type="string">Craftsman</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>Beginning at 2nd level, an aegis gains a +1 bonus to any one Craft skill of his choice.</p>
					<p>At 6th level and every four levels thereafter, this bonus increases by 1.</p>
				</benefit>
			</craftsman>
			<damagereduction>
				<name type="string">Damage Reduction</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>Starting at 2nd level, when an aegis is wearing his astral suit, he gains damage reduction 2/-,</p>
					<p>regardless of what type of astral suit he is wearing.</p>
					<p>At 5th level and every three levels thereafter, this damage reduction improves by 1.</p>
				</benefit>
			</damagereduction>
			<invigoratingsuit>
				<name type="string">Invigorating Suit (Su)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>An aegis of at least 3rd level wearing his astral suit gains a +4 bonus on the following checks and saves:</p>
					<p>Swim checks made to resist nonlethal damage from exhaustion;</p>
					<p>Constitution checks made to continue running;</p>
					<p>Constitution checks made to avoid nonlethal damage from a forced march;</p>
					<p>Constitution checks made to hold breath;</p>
					<p>Constitution checks made to avoid nonlethal damage from starvation or thirst;</p>
					<p>Fortitude saves made to avoid nonlethal damage from hot or cold environments;</p>
					<p>and Fortitude saves made to resist damage from suffocation.</p>
				</benefit>
			</invigoratingsuit>
			<reconfigure>
				<name type="string">Reconfigure</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>Starting at 3rd level, an aegis can reconfigure up to his Intelligence modifier in customization points on his astral suit once per day as a standard action.</p>
					<p>Every two levels thereafter, he can use this ability an additional time per day.</p>
				</benefit>
			</reconfigure>
			<augmentsuit>
				<name type="string">Augment Suit (Su)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>An aegis learns how to infuse his astral suit with his psionic power, augmenting the capacity of his suit.</p>
					<p>Beginning at 4th level, the aegis may spend up to one power point per four class levels to customize his Astral Suit,</p>
					<p>gaining one temporary customization point for each power point spent.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>This ability, activated as a standard action, lasts for a number of rounds equal to the aegis' Intelligence modifier.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>Activating this ability again, while already in use, immediately causes the previous duration to end.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>An aegis may end the duration as a free action at any time.</p>
				</benefit>
			</augmentsuit>
			<mastercraftsman>
				<name type="string">Master Craftsman</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>At 5th level, an aegis gains the Master Craftsman feat as a bonus feat.</p>
					<p>He must still meet the prerequisites of the feat in order to gain its benefits.</p>
				</benefit>
			</mastercraftsman>
			<cannibalizesuit>
				<name type="string">Cannibalize Suit (Su)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>Starting at 12th level, an aegis learns to convert the psionic energy used to create his suit into healing power.</p>
					<p>Once per day as a standard action, he can dismiss his astral suit and heal a number of hit points equal to his customization pool.</p>
					<p>The aegis cannot reform his suit again for one minute after using this ability.</p>
					<p>Every two levels thereafter, the aegis can use this ability an additional time per day.</p>
					<p>Additional customization points gained from Augment Suit are not counted for this ability.</p>
				</benefit>
			</cannibalizesuit>
			<perfectmerger>
				<name type="string">Perfect Merger (Su)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>An aegis of 20th level has learned to become one with his suit.</p>
					<p>His suit cannot be dispelled or removed against his will by any means, although his astral suit ability</p>
					<p>still does not function within areas where psionics do not work, such as a null psionics field.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>In addition, the aegis can spend two daily uses of his reconfigure ability to alter all of the customizations</p>
					<p>on his astral suit.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>Finally, once per day, the aegis can boost his cannibalize suit ability, healing all of his hit point damage,</p>
					<p>although he cannot reform his suit for ten minutes after using this ability, rather than the standard one minute.</p>
				</benefit>
			</perfectmerger>
		</aegis>
		<artifacer>
			<elbowgrease>
				<name type="string">Elbow Grease</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>The artificer gains a +2 bonus to all Craft checks. This bonus raises to +4 at 6th level, and +6 at 10th level.</p>
				</benefit>
			</elbowgrease>
			<jackofalltrades>
				<name type="string">Jack of All Trades</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>The artificer has picked up a smattering of even the most obscure skills. They may use any skill untrained.</p>
				</benefit>
			</jackofalltrades>
			<weirdscience>
				<name type="string">Weird Science</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>An artificer is not a spellcaster, but instead possesses the ability to imbue items with magical power.</p>
					<p>This weird science allows the artificer to create devices that combine the effects of one or more spells, either arcane or divine.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>An artificer has access to both arcane and divine spell lists, but only up to 4th level.</p>
					<p>Any number of spells can be combined into a single device. Spell statistics (casting times, etc.) remain unchanged,</p>
					<p>although no components are required and the artificer is considered the "caster" for the purposes of CL.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>Weird science devices must be invented in advance, however -- they cannot be created on the fly.</p>
					<p>The time to create such devices is 4 hours per spell level used. As such, an artificer usually has a fixed collection of</p>
					<p>regularly-carried devices.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>Weird science devices are temporary and unreliable. They are able to be used reliably a number of times per day equal to</p>
					<p>1 plus half the class level of the artificer who built the device (rounding up, naturally).</p>
					<p>The device may be used by anyone -- but if used by someone other than the artificer who built it, it requires a Use Magic Device</p>
					<p>roll at DC 15 to activate (a failed roll indicates that the device fails to activate for that user, and a roll of 1 means that the</p>
					<p>device breaks down for good).</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>If the device is used more times than allowed (by anyone), it requires a Use Magic Device skill check with a DC equal starting at</p>
					<p>20 and rising by 1 every additional time the device is used. A failed roll means that the device breaks down and may not be used</p>
					<p>again (the artificer will have to build another).</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>Combining multiple magical effects into a single device means that both effects function simultaneously upon activation</p>
					<p>(effectively casting two or more spells at once) -- but such devices are even more unstable than usual:</p>
					<p>The Use Magic Device check for extra activations starts at DC 25 + the number of effects used,</p>
					<p>and goes up for each additional usage by the number of effects used.</p>
				</benefit>
			</weirdscience>
			<itemcreation>
				<name type="string">Item Creation</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>At second level, an artificer's invention ability expands to include the creation of true magic items,</p>
					<p>even if the artificer does not have access to the prerequisite spells. The artificer must make a successful Craft check (DC 20 + caster level)</p>
					<p>to emulate each spell normally required to create the item. This ability does not stack with the Master Craftsman feat.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>The magic item creation guidelines are used, and for the purpose of emulating prerequisites, the artificer's effective CL</p>
					<p>equals his class level +2. However, if the item duplicates a spell effect, the statistics of that effect use the artificer's actual level.</p>
				</benefit>
			</itemcreation>
			<bonusfeats>
				<name type="string">Bonus Feats</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>An artificer gains every item creation feat as a bonus feat.</p>
					<p>He gets Scribe Scroll as a bonus feat at 2nd level,</p>
					<p>Brew Potion at 3rd level,</p>
					<p>Craft Wondrous Item at 4th level,</p>
					<p>Craft Magic Arms and Armor at 5th level,</p>
					<p>Craft Wand at 7th level,</p>
					<p>Craft Rod at 9th level,</p>
					<p>Craft Staff at 12th level,</p>
					<p>and Forge Ring at 14th level.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>In addition, an artificer gains a bonus feat at 3rd, 8th, 12th, 16th and 19th level.</p>
					<p>For each of these bonus feats, the artificer must choose a feat from the following list:</p>
					<p>Empower Spell, Enlarge Spell, Extend Spell, Heighten Spell, Magical Aptitude, Maximize Spell,</p>
					<p>Quicken Spell, Silent Spell, Skill Focus, Still Spell, Widen Spell.</p>
				</benefit>
			</bonusfeats>
			<salvage>
				<name type="string">Salvage</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>At 5th level, an artificer gains the ability to salvage the gold piece value from a magic item and use those funds to create</p>
					<p>another magic item. The artificer must spend a day with the item, and he must also have the appropriate item creation feat for the</p>
					<p>item he is salvaging. After one day, the item is destroyed and the artificer gains the gp value it took to create the item.</p>
					<p>This value is cannot be spent as gold, it may only be used in the creation of another magic item.</p>
				</benefit>
			</salvage>
			<metamagicscience>
				<name type="string">Metamagic Science</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>At 6th level, an artificer gains the ability to apply a metamagic feat he knows to a spell trigger item (such as a wand).</p>
					<p>He must have the appropriate item creation feat for the spell trigger item he is using. Using this ability expends additional</p>
					<p>charges from the item equal to the number of effective spell levels the metamagic feat would add to a spell.</p>
				</benefit>
			</metamagicscience>
			<improvedmetamagicscience>
				<name type="string">Improved Metamagic Science</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>At 11th level, an artificer gains the ability to apply a metamagic feat he knows to a spell completion item (a scroll, for example).</p>
					<p>He must have the appropriate item creation feat for the spell completion item he is using. The DC for the Use Magic Device check is</p>
					<p>equal to 20 + (3 times the modified level of the spell).</p>
				</benefit>
			</improvedmetamagicscience>
			<improvedjackofalltrades>
				<name type="string">Improved Jack of All Trades</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>All skills are now considered class skills for the artificer, receiving the usual +3 bonus given to class skill checks.</p>
				</benefit>
			</improvedjackofalltrades>
			<exemplar>
				<name type="string">Exemplar</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>The artificer's Jack of All Trades ability reaches its zenith: The artificer may now add half his class level to all untrained skill checks.</p>
				</benefit>
			</exemplar>
		</artifacer>
		<cryptic>
			<patterndesigns>
				<name type="string">Pattern Designs (Su)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>Unlike normal manifesters, a cryptic manipulates the world around her by creating tattoos and patterns that alters reality in different</p>
					<p>ways. Cryptic powers show up on the cryptic's body in the form of tattoos. The cryptic's known powers can be identified via Spellcraft</p>
					<p>checks with a DC equal to 10 + double the power's level. These tattoos do not count against the number of psionic tattoos that the cryptic</p>
					<p>can safely wear.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>When a cryptic manifests one of her powers, it creates a visual pattern of energy during the action taken to manifest the pattern.</p>
					<p>While the cryptic's powers have the normal displays for psionic powers - auditory, mental, and the like - this visual pattern unique to</p>
					<p>the cryptic cannot be suppressed as normal displays can be suppressed.</p>
				</benefit>
			</patterndesigns>
			<altereddefense>
				<name type="string">Altered Defense (Su)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>A cryptic learns early on to modify the patterns around her to grant her protection as a swift action.</p>
					<p>The cryptic chooses from the options below and may only have one such effect active at any given time.</p>
					<p>The cryptic can use this ability for a number of rounds per day equal to 4 + her Intelligence modifier.</p>
					<p>The cryptic can maintain this ability as long as she wants as long as she has rounds available, or dismiss it at any time as a free action.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>    Absorb: The cryptic gains DR 1/-.</p>
					<p></p>
 					<p>    Deflect: The cryptic gains a +1 dodge bonus to his AC.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>    Retaliate: The cryptic gains a +1 bonus on his attack rolls against any opponent that successfully hit him since his last turn.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>Every four cryptic levels thereafter, this bonus increases by 1 (to 2 at 5th level, 3 at 9th level, 4 at 13th level, and 5 at 17th level).</p>
				</benefit>
			</altereddefense>
			<disruptpattern>
				<name type="string">Disrupt Pattern (Su)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>All cryptics are able to disrupt the patterns they can perceive, although the potency of this disruption is based on the cryptic's focus.</p>
					<p>When a cryptic gains psionic focus, she selects one creature type as her active type (she does not need to select a subtype).</p>
					<p>As a standard action, the cryptic can make a ranged touch attack with a range of 30 feet, firing a ray of black energy at the target.</p>
					<p>If the attack is successful, the cryptic deals 1d6 points of damage + additional damage equal to the cryptic's Intelligence modifier.</p>
					<p>This attack deals half damage if the target's type is not of the cryptic's active type. Like some other rays, if the attack roll of this ability would</p>
					<p>indicate a critical hit, the damage is doubled. This ability can only be used once per round, even if an item or other effect would duplicate it.</p>
				</benefit>
			</disruptpattern>
			<lesserinsights>
				<name type="string">Lesser Insights</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>Cryptics learn minor powers they can use at will to aid them in a variety of ways. The cryptic gains 2 talents from the cryptic talent list.</p>
				</benefit>
			</lesserinsights>
			<scribetattoo>
				<name type="string">Scribe Tattoo</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>At 1st level, cryptics receive Scribe Tattoo as a bonus feat. A cryptic can scribe tattoos of any power she knows (up to 3rd level).</p>
					<p>The power must be one that can be made into a tattoo. The cryptic does not need to meet the prerequisites for this feat.</p>
				</benefit>
			</scribetattoo>
			<trapfinding>
				<name type="string">Trapfinding</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>A cryptic adds 1/2 her level to Perception skill checks made to locate traps and to Disable Device skill checks (minimum +1).</p>
					<p>A cryptic can use Disable Device to disarm magic traps.</p>
				</benefit>
			</trapfinding>
			<trapmaker>
				<name type="string">Trapmaker</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>A cryptic gains a competence bonus on Craft (traps) checks equal to her class level.</p>
				</benefit>
			</trapmaker>
			<hiddenpattern>
				<name type="string">Hidden Pattern (Ex)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>A cryptic learns how to recognize patterns in light and sound around her that can help her to mask her presence.</p>
					<p>At 2nd level, a cryptic gains a +2 competence bonus on all Stealth checks. This bonus increases to +4 at 5th level, and then again to +6 at 8th level.</p>
					<p>At 10th level, as long as the cryptic maintains psionic focus, she can use the Stealth skill to hide, even while being observed.</p>
				</benefit>
			</hiddenpattern>
			<insight>
				<name type="string">Insight (Su)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>Starting at 2nd level, and then again every 2 levels thereafter (up to 18th level),</p>
					<p>a cryptic learns a unique ability related to her perception of the patterns in the world around her.</p>
				</benefit>
			</insight>
			<enhanceddisruption>
				<name type="string">Enhanced Disruption</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>At 3rd level and every two levels thereafter, the cryptic's disrupt pattern deals an additional 1d6 points of damage.</p>
					<p>This additional damage is not multiplied on a critical hit or by using feats such as Vital Strike, but it is halved if the creature</p>
					<p>struck is not of the cryptic's active creature type.</p>
				</benefit>
			</enhanceddisruption>
			<evasion>
				<name type="string">Evasion (Ex)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>At 3rd level and higher, a cryptic can avoid even magical and unusual attacks with great agility.</p>
					<p>If she makes a successful Reflex saving throw against an attack that normally deals half damage on a successful save, she instead takes no damage.</p>
					<p>Evasion can be used only if the cryptic is wearing light armor or no armor. A helpless cryptic does not gain the benefit of evasion.</p>
				</benefit>
			</evasion>
			<rapiddefense>
				<name type="string">Rapid Defense (Su)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>Starting at 4th level, a cryptic can use her altered defense ability as a free action by expending her psionic focus.</p>
					<p>The cryptic may even do this when it is not her turn.</p>
				</benefit>
			</rapiddefense>
			<swifttrapper>
				<name type="string">Swift Trapper (Ex)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>At 6th level, a cryptic can create traps with astounding speed. It takes a cryptic half the normal amount of time to create traps.</p>
				</benefit>
			</swifttrapper>
			<enduringdefense>
				<name type="string">Enduring Defense</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>A cryptic of 14th level can choose any option from the altered defense ability and always be under that effect.</p>
					<p>The cryptic can still change the effect as a swift action, but she is no longer limited to how many rounds per day she can have Altered Defense active.</p>
				</benefit>
			</enduringdefense>
			<unchangingpattern>
				<name type="string">Unchanging Pattern</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>At 18th level, the cryptic gains power resistance equal to 12 + her class level.</p>
				</benefit>
			</unchangingpattern>
			<supremeinsight>
				<name type="string">Supreme Insight (Su)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>At 20th level, the cryptic makes astounding leaps of insight. She immediately learns two normal insights, but also learns a third insight</p>
					<p>chosen from the list to the right, representing a truly astounding breakthrough in understanding how patterns work. For many cryptics,</p>
					<p>the possibility of this sort of discoveries is the driving force for their studying of patterns.</p>
				</benefit>
			</supremeinsight>
		</cryptic>
		<tactician>
			<collective>
				<name type="string">Collective (Su)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>A tactician learns to use psionic power to connect willing minds through an internal network that strengthens their psychic bonds.</p>
					<p>As a standard action, a tactician can join any number of willing targets into his collective (up to his limit, see below).</p>
					<p>The tactician must have line of sight to each target, each target must have a Wisdom score of at least 1, and all targets must be within</p>
					<p>Medium range (100 ft. + 10 ft. per class level). The collective can contain up to his key ability modifier or half his tactician level, whichever is higher.</p>
					<p>The tactician is always considered a member of his own collective, and does not count against this limit.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>The tactician can choose to remove a member as a free action on his turn, and any member can voluntarily leave the collective as a free action on their turn.</p>
					<p>Any member whose Wisdom drops to zero or who moves out of range of the collective is automatically removed.</p>
					<p>If a member enters a null psionics field, the connection to the collective is suppressed until the member leaves the field.</p>
					<p>A member who leaves the collective for any reason immediately loses any and all benefits they may have gained from being a member.</p>
					<p>A tactician is aware of the status of his collective and can, roughly, sense the presence of each member, although beyond telling if such a creature</p>
					<p>is still a member, this has no mechanical benefit until higher levels (see telepathy below).</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>A tactician can manifest certain powers through his collective. If a tactician power specifies one or more willing targets (or is harmless) and has a</p>
					<p>range greater than personal, he can manifest this power on a member of his collective regardless of the range of the actual power. All other non-range</p>
					<p>restrictions still apply. He may manifest any power with the Network Descriptor this way, regardless of their actual ranges or targets.</p>
					<p>If he is capable of manifesting powers or casting spells from a different class (as is the case for a multiclass tactician), any compatible spell or power</p>
					<p>with a range greater than touch can also be used through the collective.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>If a member of the collective dies, the member is removed from the collective and the tactician must make a Fortitude save (DC 15) or lose 1 power point</p>
					<p>for every Hit Die of the fallen member or be sickened for an equal number of rounds.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>At 15th level, a tactician's collective range is limitless on the same plane as the tactician</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>At 19th level, a tactician's range reaches even across other planes and dimensions.</p>
				</benefit>
			</collective>
			<coordinatedstrike>
				<name type="string">Coordinated Strike (Su)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>The tacician is able to direct his allies to coordinating their attacks upon a single target to devastating effect. As a swift action,</p>
					<p>the tactician can declare one target within his line of sight as the primary foe. All members of the tactician's collective, including the</p>
					<p>tactician himself gain a +1 insight bonus to attacks against the primary foe until the beginning of the tactician's next turn.</p>
					<p>At 5th level and every four levels thereafter, this bonus increases by 1.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>This ability may be used a number of times per day equal to 3 + the tacticians Intelligence modifier.</p>
				</benefit>
			</coordinatedstrike>
			<lesserstrategies>
				<name type="string">Lesser Strategies</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>Tacticians learn minor powers they can use at will to aid them in coordination and tactics. The tactician gains 3 talents from the tactician talent list.</p>
				</benefit>
			</lesserstrategies>
			<spiritofmany>
				<name type="string">Spirit of Many (Su)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>A tactician of 2nd level gains special abilities when manifesting powers with the Network descriptor.</p>
					<p>He can manifest these powers on any member of his collective, even if they are out of the power's range or would normally be immune to the power.</p>
					<p>Whenever a tactician manifests a power with the Network descriptor targeting only members of his collective, the power loses the</p>
					<p>mind-affecting descriptor (if it had it) and is treated as a supernatural ability (bypassing Power Resistance and becoming immune to dispel attempts),</p>
					<p>although it still provokes an attacks of opportunity to manifest as normal. Network powers manifest only on members of the collective never allow</p>
					<p>saving throws - their saving throw entry becomes "None," although if the power specifies a subsequent saving throw, subjects attempt those saves normally.</p>
					<p>The tactician also adds the following augment to all powers with the network descriptor:</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>Augment: For every additional power point you spent, you can choose an additional target, so long as the target is a member of your collective.</p>
				</benefit>
			</spiritofmany>
			<telepathy>
				<name type="string">Telepathy (Su)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>When a tactician reaches 3rd level, all willing members of his collective (including the tactician himself) can communicate with each</p>
					<p>other telepathically, even if they do not share a common language. Psionic creatures who are willing members in a tactician's collective</p>
					<p>(including the tactician himself) may manifest unknown powers known by another willing psionic creature in the collective as if they were</p>
					<p>making physical contact.</p>
				</benefit>
			</telepathy>
			<strategy>
				<name type="string">Strategy (Su)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>At 4th level, and every three tactician levels thereafter, a tactician learns a new tactical strategy, granting him special abilities in combat.</p>
					<p>Unless specified otherwise, using a strategy is a swift action that does not provoke attacks of opportunity. Strategies are often orders or suggestions</p>
					<p>that the tactician issues to members of his collective. A tactician may not direct a strategy at himself unless a strategy specifies otherwise.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>Strategies may be used a number of times per day equal to 3 + the tactician's Charisma modifier.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>The tactician chooses his strategy from the list below.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>Collective Defenses:The tactician is able to harness the sensory information available through his collective to bolster the defenses of members of</p>
					<p>his collective. For a number of rounds equal to the tactician's Charisma modifier (minimum 1), the tactician and all members of his collective within</p>
					<p>line of sight of the tactician gain an insight bonus to Armor Class equal to the tactician's Intelligence modifier (minimum 1).</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>Coordinated Distraction: The tactician can direct a member of his collective to attack a single enemy, granting the directed member a +1 competence bonus</p>
					<p>on the attack roll for a number of rounds equal to the tactician's Charisma modifier (minimum 1). If the directed member performs the attack, regardless</p>
					<p>of where the directed member is in relation to the tactician, the tactician treats the enemy as being flanked and the tactician may make a single melee</p>
					<p>attack against the targeted enemy as an Immediate action. The tactician may only make one such attack per use of this strategy. Alternatively, the</p>
					<p>tactician may make the initial attack against the targeted enemy, gaining the +1 flanked, but but using the strategy in this fashion makes it a</p>
					<p>full-round action instead of a swift action. At 8th level and every four tactician levels thereafter, the competence bonus on the attack roll increases by 1.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>Coordinated Maneuvers:The tactician can sense when opponents have become vulnerable to different kinds of attack and direct his allies to capitalize on</p>
					<p>these weaknesses, granting members of his collective a +1 insight bonus on one type of combat maneuver attempt, such as bull rushes or repositions, for</p>
					<p>a number of rounds equaling his Charisma modifier (minimum 1). The tactician chooses the kind of maneuver this benefit applies to when he activates this</p>
					<p>strategy. At 8th level and every four levels thereafter, the insight bonus increases by 1.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>Directed Assault:The tactician directs a member of his collective to attack a particular target, granting this ally a +1 competence bonus on the attack</p>
					<p>roll for a number of rounds equal to the tactician's Charisma modifier (minimum 1). If the attack is made, the tactician may immediately make a single</p>
					<p>attack at any target within range as an immediate action. This attack does not count as an attack action, so does not qualify for special abilities that</p>
					<p>can be used with an attack action, such as Vital Strike. At 8th level and every four tactical levels thereafter, the competence bonus increases by 1.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>Disruptive Terrain:The tactician charges the terrain around him with psychokinetic energy. Any creature not in the tactician's collective treats the</p>
					<p>terrain as difficult terrain for a number of rounds equal to the tactician's Charisma modifier (minimum 1). The area of terrain affected is a burst</p>
					<p>effect centered on the tactician with a range of 5 feet per three tactician levels. The affected area does not change if the tactician moves after using</p>
					<p>this strategy. Selecting this strategy requires the tactician to be at least 10th level.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>Distracting Gaze:The tactician can target one enemy within 30 feet and make a ranged touch attack against that enemy. If the attack is successful, that</p>
					<p>enemy is treated as if the tactician was adjacent to him for the purposes of determining if he is flanked for a number of rounds equal to the tactician's</p>
					<p>Charisma modifier (minimum 1). Treat the direction for flanking as the direction of the tactician. Selecting this strategy requires the tactician to be</p>
					<p>at least 7th level.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>Focus Attack:The tactician can direct a member of his collective to attack a single enemy. If the directed member performs the attack, all subsequent</p>
					<p>attacks on that target for the next round by anyone in the collective deal an additional 1d6 points of damage. An individual gains this additional</p>
					<p>damage on only one successful attack per round, even if they make multiple successful attacks on the targeted enemy. At 8th level and every four</p>
					<p>tactician levels thereafter, this damage increases by 1d6.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>Guard Target:The tactician directs a member of his collective to guard a specific target (which may be the tactician, but not the directed member),</p>
					<p>granting the directed member a +1 competence bonus to attack rolls. In addition, the directed member can spend an attack of opportunity to redirect</p>
					<p>an attack made at the target as if it was made at him, even if the attack itself would not normally have provoked an attack of opportunity. Anytime</p>
					<p>the directed member redirects an attack in this fashion, the tactician gains a cumulative +1 bonus to his next attack against the source of the</p>
					<p>redirected attack. This effect lasts a number of rounds equal to the tactician's Charisma modifier (minimum 1). If the directed member would not</p>
					<p>normally be able to make an attack of opportunity, for example, if they already made one and do not possess the Combat Reflexes feat, they may not</p>
					<p>redirect attacks. At 8th level and every four tactician levels thereafter, the competence bonus on attack rolls increases by 1.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>Hold Position:The tactician can direct a member of his collective to hold their ground, granting the directed member a +1 dodge bonus to AC and a +1</p>
					<p>competence bonus to attack rolls for a number of rounds equal to the tactician's Charisma modifier (minimum 1). For each round the directed member</p>
					<p>does not move from the spot, the tactician may immediately take a free move action on the same round, but must move toward the directed member in as</p>
					<p>direct a manner as possible. The tactician gains a +1 dodge bonus to his AC during this move. At 8th level and every four tactician levels thereafter,</p>
					<p>the dodge bonuses and the competence bonus to attack rolls increase by 1.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>Into the Fray:The tactician directs a member of his collective to charge a particular enemy, granting the ally a +1 competence bonus on the damage roll.</p>
					<p>If the charge is performed, the tactician may charge the same enemy as an immediate action, gaining a +1 competence bonus on the damage roll.</p>
					<p>At 8th level and every four tactician levels thereafter, the competence bonus increases by 1</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>Reposition: The tactician direct each ally in collective to take a 5-foot step as a free action immediately. The tactician may also immediately take a</p>
					<p>5-foot step. This does not count against the number of 5-foot steps allowed in the tactician's or each ally's turns. If all directed allies takes their</p>
					<p>5-foot step, the tactician may immediately make a full attack against any target within range and gain a +1 competence bonus on the attack and damage rolls.</p>
					<p>Selecting this strategy to be at least a 13th level tactician. At 16th level and every four tactician levels thereafter, the competence bonus increases by 1.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>Telempathic Resistance: The tactician shares not only thoughts, but also resilience to members of his collective. For a number of rounds equal to the</p>
					<p>tactician's Charisma modifier (minimum 1), all members of the tactician's collective gain a +1 insight bonus to saving throws At 8th level and every</p>
					<p>four tactician levels thereafter, the insight bonus increases by 1.</p>
				</benefit>
			</strategy>
			<improvedshare>
				<name type="string">Improved Share (Su)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>A tactician learns special techniques when manifesting powers with the Shared descriptor. Beginning at 5th level, the tactician may maintain</p>
					<p>two powers with the Shared descriptor at any time instead of only one. Should he manifest a third power with the Shared descriptor, the tactician</p>
					<p>can choose which of the maintained Shared powers ends immediately.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>Every six tactician levels thereafter (11th, 17th), the tactician may maintain an additional power with the Shared descriptor before a maintained</p>
					<p>power with the Shared descriptor expires.</p>
				</benefit>
			</improvedshare>
			<coordinate>
				<name type="string">Coordinate (Su)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>At 6th level, as long as the tactician maintains psionic focus, he may share any one teamwork feat he has with one member of his collective within</p>
					<p>line of sight and line of effect. Declaring which member of the collective gains the teamwork feat is a free action that can only be done once per round.</p>
					<p>The ally's positioning and actions must still meet the prerequisites listed in the teamwork feat to receive the listed bonus, but the ally need not meet</p>
					<p>the feat prerequisites to gain the benefit.</p>
				</benefit>
			</coordinate>
			<teamworkfeat>
				<name type="string">Teamwork Feat</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>At 6th level, and every six levels thereafter, the tactician gains a bonus feat in addition to those gained from normal advancement.</p>
					<p>These bonus feats must be selected from those listed as teamwork feats. The tactician must meet the prerequisites of the selected bonus feat.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>By spending one hour in meditation, the tactician can change anyone teamwork feat he has already learned for another teamwork feat whose prerequisites</p>
					<p>he meets. In effect, the tactician loses the bonus feat in exchange for a new one.</p>
				</benefit>
			</teamworkfeat>
			<echoeffect>
				<name type="string">Echo Effect (Su)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>At 8th level, the tactician gains the ability to copy non-permanent magical and psionic effects within his collective. If a member of the collective</p>
					<p>is affected by a magical or psionic effect with a duration greater than 1 round, the tactician can echo it onto another member of his collective.</p>
					<p>To do so the tactician must first identify the power properly (see the Spellcraft skill description).</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>Echoing a magical or psionic effect is a standard action that provokes attacks of opportunity and costs the tactician a number of power points equal</p>
					<p>to the original effect's caster or manifester level (whichever applies). As a supernatural ability, a tactician is permitted to spend more power points</p>
					<p>than his manifest level on this effect. The new target must be legal for the effect in question (for instance, if you attempt to echo an unaugmented</p>
					<p>Empathic Connection on a dog, the echo will fail). If the effect allows a saving throw, the new target is entitled to a saving throw when the effect is</p>
					<p>echoed (same DC as the original power).</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>Only the basic effect and augmentation are echoed: metamagic and metapsionic feats do not echo. The echo has all the same decisions made as the original.</p>
					<p>For example, Specified Energy Adaption echoes would guard against the same energy type, while a 5pp Empathic Connection (extended duration) could not be</p>
					<p>echoed as a 5pp Empathic Connection (affects aberrations). The echo takes effect at the same caster or manifester level as the originator. When the</p>
					<p>original ends or leaves the collective, all echoes of it also end. An echo can be dispelled as normal without terminating the original.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>A tactician can spend power points to augment this supernatural ability. For every 4 additional power points spent, the echo may reach an additional target.</p>
					<p>If the augment would raise the cost of the echo above the tactician's manifester level, the echo attempt fail (although he may still attempt to echo it onto</p>
					<p>a single target). The tactician knows if an effect is beyond his ability to echo this way when he identifies it.</p>
				</benefit>
			</echoeffect>
			<pooledknowledge>
				<name type="string">Pooled Knowledge (Su)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>Once a tactician has reached 14th level, he has learned to share not only strategic knowledge over the collective, but even knowledge of manifesting.</p>
					<p>By expending psionic focus, the tactician may attempt to manifest any power known by a member of his collective. If the power is not on the tactician</p>
					<p>power list, the tactician must make a successful Spellcraft check (DC 20 + the power's level) to see if he understands the power. If the Spellcraft check</p>
					<p>fails, the attempt fails and psionic focus is still expended, but no power points are spent. If the check is successful, the tactician may immediately</p>
					<p>manifest the power. Using this ability uses an action equal to the manifesting time of the power to be manifested. This ability may not be used to</p>
					<p>manifest powers with a manifesting time longer than one round.</p>
				</benefit>
			</pooledknowledge>
			<masterstrategist>
				<name type="string">Master Strategist (Su)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>Upon achieving 20th level, a tactician has learned how to turn his collective into a truly cohesive battle unit. The tactician may use two</p>
					<p>daily uses of his strategy ability and grant all of his allies an insight bonus on attack and damage rolls, armor class, and saving throws equal</p>
					<p>to his intelligence for two minutes. This ability may not be used if the tactician is not engaged in combat.</p>
				</benefit>
			</masterstrategist>
		</tactician>
		<vitalist>
			<knacks>
				<name type="string">Knacks (Ps)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>Vitalists of all forms learn to manipulate the energy of body and mind in minor ways. A vitalist gains two talents from the vitalist power list,</p>
					<p>as well as one talent from his method power list.</p>
				</benefit>
			</knacks>
			<collective>
				<name type="string">Collective (Su)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>A vitalist learns to use psionic power to connect willing minds through an internal network that strengthens their psychic bonds.</p>
					<p>As a standard action, a vitalist can join a number willing targets into his collective equal to his key ability modifier or half his vitalist</p>
					<p>level, whichever is higher. The vitalist must have line of sight to each target, each target must have a Wisdom score of at least 1, and all</p>
					<p>targets must be within Medium range (100 ft. + 10 ft. per class level). The vitalist is always considered a member of his own collective,</p>
					<p>and does not count against this limit.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>The vitalist can choose to remove a member as a free action on his turn, and any member can voluntarily leave the collective as a free action</p>
					<p>on their turn. Any member whose Wisdom drops to zero or who moves out of range of the collective is automatically removed. If a member enters</p>
					<p>a null psionics field, the connection to the collective is suppressed until that member leaves the field. A member who leaves the collective</p>
					<p>for any reason immediately loses any and all benefits they may have gained from being a member. A vitalist is aware of the status of his collective</p>
					<p>and can, roughly, sense the presence of each member, although beyond telling if such a creature is still a member, this has no mechanical benefit</p>
					<p>until higher levels (see telepathy and health sense, below).</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>A vitalist can manifest certain powers through his collective. If a vitalist power specifies one or more willing targets (or is harmless) and</p>
					<p>has a range greater than personal, he can manifest this power on a member of his collective regardless of the range of the actual power. All other</p>
					<p>non-range restrictions still apply. He may also manifest any power with the Network descriptor this way, regardless of their actual ranges or targets.</p>
					<p>If he is capable of manifesting powers or casting spells from a different class (as is the case for a multiclass vitalist), any compatible spell</p>
					<p>or power with a range greater than touch can also be used through the collective.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>If a member of the collective dies, the member is removed from the collective and the vitalist must make a Fortitude save (DC 15) or</p>
					<p>lose 1 power point for every Hit Die of the fallen member and be sickened for an equal number of rounds.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>    At 15th level, a vitalist's collective range is limitless on the same plane as the vitalist.</p>
					<p>    At 19th level, a vitalist's collective reaches even across to other planes and dimensions.</p>
				</benefit>
			</collective>
			<collectivehealing>
				<name type="string">Collective Healing (Su)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>Whenever a willing member of the vitalist's collective could regain lost hit points or ability damage, the vitalist may choose to redirect</p>
					<p>any or all of that healing to one or more other willing members of the collective as a free action. This can transfer instantaneous healing</p>
					<p>(such as a body adjustment power), healing from ongoing healing effects, such as fast healing, and even hit points gained from rest (in which</p>
					<p>case, a member of the collective would rest for a period of time as normal, and the amount of hit points and ability damage healed would go to another).</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>In any case, the original recipient of the healing effect chooses whether to allow the diverted healing, and does not gain the benefits of any</p>
					<p>healing he grants to another. The type of healing (positive energy, negative energy, construct repair, etc.) is unchanged from the original source</p>
					<p>for determining who or what can be healed.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>Example: Darius the soulknife is a willing member of Jorus the vitalist's collective. He drinks a potion of cure light wounds that would normally</p>
					<p>heal him for 6 hit points, but Jorus decides to redirect 4 of those points to himself. Darius agrees and, as a result, Darius is healed for 2 hit</p>
					<p>points, and Jorus is healed for 4. If there were more members in Jorus's collective, Jorus could spread the healing from that potion out even more</p>
					<p>as long as the sum of hit points healed was no greater than 6.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>A vitalist may even heal wounds through collective healing if at full health. This may only be used with healing effects such as potions, powers,</p>
					<p>or other such effects. [Healing] from long term care or natural healing cannot be transferred in this way.</p>
				</benefit>
			</collectivehealing>
			<medicpowers>
				<name type="string">Medic Powers</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>The vitalist gains special uses of some of his powers that are unavailable to other characters.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>The following powers gain the Network descriptor when manifested by a vitalist:</p>
					<p>all powers of the [healing] subdiscipline, animal affinity, biofeedback, body of iron, endorphin surge, expansion,</p>
					<p>oak body, physical acceleration, sustenance, suspend life, timeless body, and vigor.</p>
				</benefit>
			</medicpowers>
			<vitaliststouch>
				<name type="string">Vitalist's Touch</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>Once a vitalist reaches 2nd level, he learns to apply the skills of his method to his transfer wounds ability, as detailed in the vitalist's method of choice.</p>
				</benefit>
			</vitaliststouch>
			<healthsense>
				<name type="string">Health Sense</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>Beginning at 2nd level, a vitalist may take a swift action to gauge the relative health level of collective members, determining the amount</p>
					<p>of damage, in hit points, that an ally has taken. In addition, the vitalist may make a Heal check as a standard action, with a DC of 15, to</p>
					<p>determine if any of the members of his collective are afflicted by a disease or poison.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>Starting at 7th level, the vitalist can make a Heal check over his collective to stabilize a dying target or treat a wound from a caltrop,</p>
					<p>spike growth, spike stones, or similar. This ability improves at 12th level, and the vitalist may make a Heal check over his collective to treat</p>
					<p>a poisoned creature.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>At 17th level, the vitalist is able to treat diseases in the same fashion, making a Heal check over his collective.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>When treating a target over a collective, the DC of the Heal check is the same as if the vitalist was treating the target normally.</p>
				</benefit>
			</healthsense>
			<spiritofmany>
				<name type="string">Spirit of Many (Su)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>A vitalist of 2nd level gains special abilities when manifesting powers with the Network descriptor. He can manifest these powers on any member</p>
					<p>of his collective, even if they are out of the power's range or would normally be immune to the power. Whenever a vitalist manifests a power with</p>
					<p>the Network descriptor targeting only members of his collective, the power loses the mind-affecting descriptor (if it had it) and bypasses any power</p>
					<p>resistance, although it still provokes an attack of opportunity to manifest as normal. Network powers manifest only on members of the collective</p>
					<p>never allow saving throws -- their saving throw entry becomes "None," although if the power specifies a subsequent saving throw, subjects attempt</p>
					<p>those saves normally. The vitalist also adds the following augment to all powers with the Network descriptor:</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>	Augment: For every additional power point you spend, you can choose an additional target, so long as the target is a member of your collective.</p>
				</benefit>
			</spiritofmany>
			<stealhealth>
				<name type="string">Steal Health (Su)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>At 3rd level, a vitalist has learned to siphon the health of a creature and use it for his own needs or the needs of his collective.</p>
					<p>As a touch attack, the vitalist may deal a number of hit points in damage to the target equal to his vitalist level + his Wisdom modifier and</p>
					<p>heal an equal amount of damage. The vitalist may share any healing from this effect over his collective, even if he himself would not be eligible</p>
					<p>for the healing. A vitalist may not heal more hit points than the touched creature had prior to using this ability.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>This ability may only be used on creatures with a Constitution score and may not be used against creatures in the vitalist's collective.</p>
					<p>A vitalist may use this ability on creatures with a total number of hit dice less than half his vitalist level, but he gains no healing from it.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>For example, Jorus is a level 3 vitalist with a Wisdom of 16 and 15 hit points. Jorus has suffered 3 hit points of damage and uses Steal Health</p>
					<p>on a nearby 2 hit dice orc, dealing 6 hit points of damage (3 from his levels in vitalist, 3 from his Wisdom modifier). Although Jorus may only</p>
					<p>heal himself for 3 hit points, he may distribute the other 3 hit points over the collective to other members as needed. If Jorus was level 6, he</p>
					<p>would have dealt 9 points of damage, but would not have received any healing because the orc's total number of hit dice was too low.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>At 7th level, a vitalist is able to use steal health as a ranged touch attack with a range of 30 feet.</p>
				</benefit>
			</stealhealth>
			<telepathy>
				<name type="string">Telepathy (Su)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>When a vitalist reaches 3rd level, all willing members of his collective (including the vitalist himself) can communicate with each</p>
					<p>other telepathically, even if they do not share a common language. Psionic creatures who are willing members in a vitalist's collective</p>
					<p>(including the vitalist himself) may manifest unknown powers from powers known by another willing psionic creature in the collective as</p>
					<p>if they were making physical contact.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>A vitalist may temporarily deactivate, and reactivate, this ability as a swift action.</p>
				</benefit>
			</telepathy>
			<requestaid>
				<name type="string">Request Aid (Su)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>Starting at 5th level, members of a vitalist's collective are able to request aid from the vitalist, should he not realize such aid is needed.</p>
					<p>As a standard action, any member of the collective can request healing from the vitalist. The vitalist can grant this request by spending up to</p>
					<p>his level in power points as a free action, even if it is not his turn. Each power point spent in this fashion heals 3 hit points to the target.</p>
					<p>A vitalist can even initiate this healing himself should he realize someone needs healing, by spending a standard action. A vitalist can do this</p>
					<p>a number of times per day equal to 3 + his Wisdom modifier.</p>
				</benefit>
			</requestaid>
			<pulse>
				<name type="string">Pulse (Su)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>A vitalist of 6th level can project an pulse of psionic energy to all members of his collective as a free action by spending 1 power point.</p>
					<p>The effect of the pulse depends on the vitalist's chosen method. The pulse lasts one round.</p>
				</benefit>
			</pulse>
			<swiftaid>
				<name type="string">Swift Aid (Su)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>Upon achieving 8th level, a vitalist is able to rapidly respond to the need of a member of his collective, as determined by his vitalist method.</p>
				</benefit>
			</swiftaid>
			<expandedknowledge>
				<name type="string">Expanded Knowledge</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>Skilled vitalists understand that there is merit in expanding their arsenal. At 9th level, a vitalist gains Expanded Knowledge as a bonus feat. He gains this feat again at 18th level.</p>
				</benefit>
			</expandedknowledge>
			<vitalistsexpertise>
				<name type="string">Vitalist's Expertise (Su)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>A vitalist of 11th level has become an expert at his chosen method, and gains the ability detailed in that method.</p>
				</benefit>
			</vitalistsexpertise>
			<steallife>
				<name type="string">Steal Life (Su)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>Beginning at 14th level, a vitalist can not only steal the health of a target, but steal their life itself. By making a successful</p>
					<p>melee touch attack and expending psionic focus, the vitalist can force the target to make a Fortitude save</p>
					<p>(DC 10 + half class level + Wisdom modifier) or die. A successful save negates this effect. Targets with more than 140 hit points are</p>
					<p>unaffected by this ability.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>If the target fails the save, the vitalist is able to channel the stolen life force through his collective, healing any number of the</p>
					<p>members of his collective for a combined total of 5 hit points per hit die the original target had.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>This ability may only be used on creatures with a Constitution score and may not be used against creatures in the vitalist's collective.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>For example, Jorus is a level 14 vitalist and he uses steal life on a thought slayer, which has 11 hit dice. The thought slayer fails</p>
					<p>the Fortitude save, so Jorus can heal up to 55 hit points over his collective, divided among the members as he sees fit.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>A vitalist must wait 10 minutes after using this ability before he can attempt to use it again. This is considered a death effect.</p>
				</benefit>
			</steallife>
			<mastervitalist>
				<name type="string">Master Vitalist (Su)</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>Upon achieving 20th level, a vitalist has reached the pinnacle of his method, gaining a special ability unique to his chosen method.</p>
				</benefit>
			</mastervitalist>
			<vitalistmethod>
				<name type="string">Vitalist Method</name>
				<type type="string">Class</type>
				<mult type="number">0</mult>
				<stack type="number">0</stack>
				<benefit type="formattedtext">
					<p>All vitalists must choose a particular method that encompasses their focus in the skills they develop. As they gain in level,</p>
					<p>their method determines the abilities they gain.</p>
				</benefit>
			</vitalistmethod>
		</vitalist>
		
		<item>
			<artifacer>
				<artifacerworkbook>
					<name type="string">Artifacer Workbook</name><isidentified type="number">1</isidentified>
					<cost type="string">200 gp</cost>
					<weight type="number">2</weight>
					<type type="string">Item</type>
					<subtype type="string">Tools and Skill Kits</subtype>
					<description type="formattedtext">
						<p>An artifacer is proficient with making items of magic and temporary items through weird science from any branch of magic.</p>
						<list>
							<li>An artifacer workbook contains the spells of domain or arcane that the artifacer knows.</li>
							<li>an artifacer will need 1 workbook for each </li>
							<li>When used as a reference, an artifacer workbook grants:</li>
							<li>+2 bonus on a craft checks.</li>
							<li>weird science inventions require 1 spell level less time to create.</li>
						</list>
					</description>
				</artifacerworkbook>
				<rodofartifacermight>
					<name type="string">Rod of Artifacer Might</name><isidentified type="number">1</isidentified>
					<description type="formattedtext">
						<p>This artifacer version of the more famous rod of lordly might has no spell-like powers; however, when wielded by an artifacer, it increases all AC, attack roll, CMD, CMB, and saving throw bonuses from a artifacer's class traits by +1. The rod shares the mundane powers of a rod of lordly might, but its magical weapon forms are tailored to an Artifacers' preferences.</p>
						<list>
							<li>In its normal form, the rod can be used as a +1 returning light mace.</li>
							<li>When button 1 is pushed, the rod becomes a +3 longspear.</li>
							<li>When button 2 is pushed, the rod becomes a +4 heavy mace.</li>
							<li>When button 3 is pushed, the rod becomes a +2 light crossbow or +2 heavy crossbow.</li>
						</list>
					</description>
					<aura type="string">strong transmutation</aura>
					<cl type="number">19</cl>
					<prerequisites type="string">Craft Magic Arms and Armor, Craft Rod, bull's strength, telekinesis, creator must be an artifacer</prerequisites>
					<cost type="string">80,000 gp</cost>
					<type type="string">Item</type>
					<subtype type="string">Magical Rod</subtype>
				</rodofartifacermight>
			</artifacer>
		</item>
	</reference>
	
	<lists static="true">
		<aegis>
			<basemenu>
				<name type="string">Aegis Class</name>
				<index>
					<r1stats>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencetextwide</class>
							<recordname>lists.aegis.statblock@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Leveling Stats</name>
					</r1stats>
					<r2proficiencies>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referenceindex</class>
							<recordname>lists.aegis.proficiencies@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Proficiencies</name>
					</r2proficiencies>
					<r3coreaegis>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referenceindex</class>
							<recordname>lists.aegis.core@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Core aegis</name>
					</r3coreaegis>
				</index>
			</basemenu>
			<statblock>
				<name type="string">aegis</name>
				<text type="formattedtext">
					<p><b>Alignment:</b> Any</p>
					<p><b>Hit Die:</b> d10</p>
					<p><b>Class Skills</b></p>
					<p>The aegis's class skills are Acrobatics (Dex), Autohypnosis* (Wis), Climb (Str), Craft (Int), Knowledge (psionics)* (Int), Profession (Wis), Spellcraft (Int), Swim (Str), and Use Magic Device (Cha).</p>
					<p><b>Skill Ranks Per Level:</b> 4 + Int modifier.</p>
					<p><b>Starting Wealth:</b> 3d6 x 10 gp (average 105 gp)</p>
					<table>
						<tr><td colspan="9"><b>Table: The aegis</b></td></tr>
						<tr decoration="underline"><td><b>Level </b></td><td colspan="2"><b>Base Attack</b></td><td><b>Fort</b></td><td><b>Ref</b></td><td><b>Will</b></td><td colspan="3"><b>Special</b></td></tr>
						<tr><td>1st</td><td colspan="2">+1</td><td>+2</td><td>+0</td><td>+2</td><td colspan="3">Astral repair, form astral suit</td></tr>
						<tr><td>2nd</td><td colspan="2">+2</td><td>+3</td><td>+0</td><td>+2</td><td colspan="3">Craftsman (+1), damage reduction (2/-)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>3rd</td><td colspan="2">+3</td><td>+3</td><td>+1</td><td>+3</td><td colspan="3">Invigorating suit, reconfigure (1/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>4th</td><td colspan="2">+4</td><td>+4</td><td>+1</td><td>+4</td><td colspan="3">Augment suit (1)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>5th</td><td colspan="2">+5</td><td>+4</td><td>+1</td><td>+4</td><td colspan="3">Damage reduction (3/-), Master Craftsman, reconfigure (2/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>6th</td><td colspan="2">+6/+1</td><td>+5</td><td>+2</td><td>+5</td><td colspan="3">Craftsman (+2)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>7th</td><td colspan="2">+7/+2</td><td>+5</td><td>+2</td><td>+5</td><td colspan="3">Reconfigure (3/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>8th</td><td colspan="2">+8/+3</td><td>+6</td><td>+2</td><td>+6</td><td colspan="3">Augment suit (2), damage reduction (4/-)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>9th</td><td colspan="2">+9/+4</td><td>+6</td><td>+3</td><td>+6</td><td colspan="3">Reconfigure (4/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>10th</td><td colspan="2">+10/+5</td><td>+7</td><td>+3</td><td>+7</td><td colspan="3">Craftsman (+3)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>11th</td><td colspan="2">+11/+6/+1</td><td>+7</td><td>+3</td><td>+7</td><td colspan="3">Damage reduction (5/-), reconfigure (5/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>12th</td><td colspan="2">+12/+7/+2</td><td>+8</td><td>+4</td><td>+8</td><td colspan="3">Augment suit (3), cannibalize suit (1/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>13th</td><td colspan="2">+13/+8/+3</td><td>+8</td><td>+4</td><td>+8</td><td colspan="3">Reconfigure (6/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>14th</td><td colspan="2">+14/+9/+4</td><td>+9</td><td>+4</td><td>+9</td><td colspan="3">Craftsman (+4), cannibalize suit (2/day), damage reduction (6/-)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>15th</td><td colspan="2">+15/+10/+5</td><td>+9</td><td>+5</td><td>+9</td><td colspan="3">Reconfigure (7/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>16th</td><td colspan="2">+16/+11/+6/+1</td><td>+10</td><td>+5</td><td>+10</td><td colspan="3">Augment suit (4), cannibalize suit (3/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>17th</td><td colspan="2">+17/+12/+7/+2</td><td>+10</td><td>+5</td><td>+10</td><td colspan="3">Damage reduction (7/-), reconfigure (8/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>18th</td><td colspan="2">+18/+13/+8/+3</td><td>+11</td><td>+6</td><td>+11</td><td colspan="3">Cannibalize suit (4/day), Craftsman (+5)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>19th</td><td colspan="2">+19/+14/+9/+4</td><td>+11</td><td>+6</td><td>+11</td><td colspan="3">Reconfigure (9/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>20th</td><td colspan="2">+20/+15/+10/+5</td><td>+12</td><td>+6</td><td>+12</td><td colspan="3">Augment suit (5), cannibalize suit (5/day), damage reduction (8/-), perfect merger</td></tr>
					</table>
					<p></p>
					<table>
						<tr><td></td><td colspan="7"><b>Table: Customization/Power points per Day</b></td></tr>
						<tr decoration="underline"><td><b>Lvl</b></td><td><b>Customization Points</b></td><td><b>Power Points/Day</b></td><td><b>Lvl</b></td><td><b>Customization Points</b></td><td><b>Power Points/Day</b></td></tr>
						<tr><td>1st</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>11th</td><td>15</td><td>24</td></tr>
						<tr><td>2nd</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>12th</td><td>16</td><td>28</td></tr>
						<tr><td>3rd</td><td>5</td><td>3</td><td>13th</td><td>17</td><td>32</td></tr>
						<tr><td>4th</td><td>7</td><td>5</td><td>14th</td><td>19</td><td>37</td></tr>
						<tr><td>5th</td><td>8</td><td>7</td><td>15th</td><td>20</td><td>42</td></tr>
						<tr><td>6th</td><td>9</td><td>9</td><td>16th</td><td>21</td><td>47</td></tr>
						<tr><td>7th</td><td>10</td><td>11</td><td>17th</td><td>22</td><td>52</td></tr>
						<tr><td>8th</td><td>11</td><td>14</td><td>18th</td><td>23</td><td>58</td></tr>
						<tr><td>9th</td><td>13</td><td>17</td><td>19th</td><td>25</td><td>64</td></tr>
						<tr><td>10th</td><td>14</td><td>20</td><td>20th</td><td>26</td><td>70</td></tr>
					</table>
					<p></p>
					<p><h1><b>Class Features</b></h1></p>
					<p></p>
					<p>The following are class features of the aegis.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p><b>Weapon and Armor Proficiencies</b></p>
					<p></p>
					<p>Aegii are proficient with all simple and martial weapons. Aegii are proficient with light armor and shields (but not tower shields).</p>
					<p>Armor does not interfere with the aegis's class features.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p><b>Power Points/Day:</b> An aegis's ability to manifest some of his abilities is limited by the power points he has available. His base daily allotment</p>
					<p>of power points is given on Table: The Aegis. In addition, he receives bonus power points per day if he has a high Intelligence score</p>
					<p>(see Table: Ability Modifiers and Bonus Power Points), treating his manifester level for the purposes of bonus power points as equal to his</p>
					<p>class level. His race may also provide bonus power points per day, as may certain feats and items.</p>
				</text>
			</statblock>
			<proficiencies>
				<name type="string">Proficiencies</name>
				<index>
					<simpleweapons>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.proficiencies.simpleweapons@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Simple Weapons</name>
					</simpleweapons>
					<lightarmor>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.proficiencies.lightarmor@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Light Armor</name>
					</lightarmor>
				</index>
			</proficiencies>
			<core>
				<name type="string">Core Aegis</name>
				<index>
					<astralrepair>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.aegis.astralrepair@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Astral Repair</name>
					</astralrepair>
					<formastralsuit>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.aegis.formastralsuit@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Form Astral Suit</name>
					</formastralsuit>
					<craftsman>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.aegis.craftsman@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Craftsman</name>
					</craftsman>
					<damagereduction>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.aegis.damagereduction@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Damage Reduction</name>
					</damagereduction>
					<invigoratingsuit>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.aegis.invigoratingsuit@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Invigorating Suit</name>
					</invigoratingsuit>
					<reconfigure>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.aegis.reconfigure@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Reconfigure</name>
					</reconfigure>
					<augmentsuit>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.aegis.augmentsuit@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Augment Suit</name>
					</augmentsuit>
					<mastercraftsman>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.aegis.mastercraftsman@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Master Craftsman</name>
					</mastercraftsman>
					<cannibalizesuit>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.aegis.cannibalizesuit@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Cannibalize Suit</name>
					</cannibalizesuit>
					<perfectmerger>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.aegis.perfectmerger@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Perfect Merger</name>
					</perfectmerger>
				</index>
			</core>
		</aegis>
		<artifacer>
			<basemenu>
				<name type="string">Artifacer Class</name>
				<index>
					<r1stats>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencetextwide</class>
							<recordname>lists.artifacer.statblock@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Leveling Stats</name>
					</r1stats>
					<r2proficiencies>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referenceindex</class>
							<recordname>lists.artifacer.proficiencies@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Proficiencies</name>
					</r2proficiencies>
					<r3coreartifacer>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referenceindex</class>
							<recordname>lists.artifacer.core@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Core Artifacer</name>
					</r3coreartifacer>
				</index>
			</basemenu>
			<statblock>
				<name type="string">Artifacer</name>
				<text type="formattedtext">
					<p><b>Alignment:</b> Any Neutral</p>
					<p><b>Hit Die:</b> d6</p>
					<p><b>Class Skills</b></p>
					<p>The artificer's class skills are Appraise (Int), Craft (Int), Diplomacy (Cha), Disable Device (Dex), Escape Artist (Dex), Knowledge (arcana) (Int), Knowledge (engineering) (Int), Perception (Wis), Linguistics (Int), Spellcraft (Int) and Use Magic Device (Cha).</p>
					<p><b>Skill Ranks Per Level:</b> 5 + Int modifier.</p>
					<p><b>Starting Wealth:</b> 3d6 x 10 gp (average 105gp)</p>
					<table>
						<tr><td colspan="9"><b>Table: The Artifacer</b></td></tr>
						<tr decoration="underline"><td><b>Level </b></td><td colspan="2"><b>Base Attack</b></td><td><b>Fort</b></td><td><b>Ref</b></td><td><b>Will</b></td><td colspan="3"><b>Special</b></td></tr>
						<tr><td>1st</td><td colspan="2">+0</td><td>+2</td><td>+0</td><td>+2</td><td colspan="3">Elbow grease, jack of all trades, weird science</td></tr>
						<tr><td>2nd</td><td colspan="2">+1</td><td>+3</td><td>+0</td><td>+2</td><td colspan="3">Item creation, scribe scroll</td></tr>
						<tr><td>3rd</td><td colspan="2">+2</td><td>+3</td><td>+1</td><td>+3</td><td colspan="3">Brew potion, bonus feat</td></tr>
						<tr><td>4th</td><td colspan="2">+3</td><td>+4</td><td>+1</td><td>+4</td><td colspan="3">Craft wondrous Item</td></tr>
						<tr><td>5th</td><td colspan="2">+3</td><td>+4</td><td>+1</td><td>+4</td><td colspan="3">Craft magic arms and armor, salvage</td></tr>
						<tr><td>6th</td><td colspan="2">+4</td><td>+5</td><td>+2</td><td>+5</td><td colspan="3">Metamagic science, elbow grease +4</td></tr>
						<tr><td>7th</td><td colspan="2">+5</td><td>+5</td><td>+2</td><td>+5</td><td colspan="3">Craft wand</td></tr>
						<tr><td>8th</td><td colspan="2">+6/+1</td><td>+6</td><td>+2</td><td>+6</td><td colspan="3">Bonus feat</td></tr>
						<tr><td>9th</td><td colspan="2">+6/+1</td><td>+6</td><td>+3</td><td>+6</td><td colspan="3">Craft rod</td></tr>
						<tr><td>10th</td><td colspan="2">+7/+2</td><td>+7</td><td>+3</td><td>+7</td><td colspan="3">Elbow grease +6</td></tr>
						<tr><td>11th</td><td colspan="2">+8/+3</td><td>+7</td><td>+3</td><td>+7</td><td colspan="3">Improved metamagic science</td></tr>
						<tr><td>12th</td><td colspan="2">+9/+4</td><td>+8</td><td>+4</td><td>+8</td><td colspan="3">Craft staff, Bonus feat</td></tr>
						<tr><td>13th</td><td colspan="2">+9/+4</td><td>+8</td><td>+4</td><td>+8</td><td colspan="3">Improved jack of all trades</td></tr>
						<tr><td>14th</td><td colspan="2">+10/+5</td><td>+9</td><td>+4</td><td>+9</td><td colspan="3">Forge ring</td></tr>
						<tr><td>15th</td><td colspan="2">+11/+6/+1</td><td>+9</td><td>+5</td><td>+9</td><td colspan="3"></td></tr>
						<tr><td>16th</td><td colspan="2">+12/+7/+2</td><td>+10</td><td>+5</td><td>+10</td><td colspan="3">Bonus feat</td></tr>
						<tr><td>17th</td><td colspan="2">+12/+7/+2</td><td>+10</td><td>+5</td><td>+10</td><td colspan="3"></td></tr>
						<tr><td>18th</td><td colspan="2">+13/+8/+3</td><td>+11</td><td>+6</td><td>+11</td><td colspan="3"></td></tr>
						<tr><td>19th</td><td colspan="2">+14/+9/+4</td><td>+11</td><td>+6</td><td>+11</td><td colspan="3">Bonus feat</td></tr>
						<tr><td>20th</td><td colspan="2">+15/+10/+5</td><td>+12</td><td>+6</td><td>+12</td><td colspan="3">Exemplar</td></tr>
					</table>
					<p></p>
					<table>
						<tr><td></td><td colspan="7"><b>Table: Weird Science Inventions</b></td></tr>
						<tr decoration="underline"><td><b>l</b></td><td><b>2</b></td><td><b>3</b></td><td><b>4</b></td><td><b>l</b></td><td><b>2</b></td><td><b>3</b></td><td><b>4</b></td></tr>
						<tr><td>1st</td><td>1</td><td>-</td><td>-</td><td>-</td><td>11th</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>1</td></tr>
						<tr><td>2nd</td><td>2</td><td>-</td><td>-</td><td>-</td><td>12th</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>1</td></tr>
						<tr><td>3rd</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>-</td><td>-</td><td>13th</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>1</td></tr>
						<tr><td>4th</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>-</td><td>-</td><td>14th</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>4</td><td>2</td></tr>
						<tr><td>5th</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>-</td><td>15th</td><td>5</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>2</td></tr>
						<tr><td>6th</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>-</td><td>16th</td><td>5</td><td>5</td><td>4</td><td>3</td></tr>
						<tr><td>7th</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td><td>-</td><td>17th</td><td>5</td><td>5</td><td>5</td><td>3</td></tr>
						<tr><td>8th</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>2</td><td>-</td><td>18th</td><td>5</td><td>5</td><td>5</td><td>4</td></tr>
						<tr><td>9th</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>-</td><td>19th</td><td>5</td><td>5</td><td>5</td><td>4</td></tr>
						<tr><td>10th</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>3</td><td>-</td><td>20th</td><td>5</td><td>5</td><td>5</td><td>5</td></tr>
					</table>
					<p></p>
					<p><b>Class Features</b></p>
					<p></p>
					<p>All of the following are class features of the artificer.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p><b>Weapon and Armor Proficiency:</b> An artificer is proficient with all simple weapons, with light armor, and with shields (except tower shields).</p>
				</text>
			</statblock>
			<proficiencies>
				<name type="string">Proficiencies</name>
				<index>
					<simpleweapons>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.proficiencies.simpleweapons@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Simple Weapons</name>
					</simpleweapons>
					<lightarmor>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.proficiencies.lightarmor@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Light Armor</name>
					</lightarmor>
				</index>
			</proficiencies>
			<core>
				<name type="string">Core Artifacer</name>
				<index>
					<elbowgrease>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.artifacer.elbowgrease@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Elbow Grease</name>
					</elbowgrease>
					<jackofalltrades>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.artifacer.jackofalltrades@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Jack of All Trades</name>
					</jackofalltrades>
					<weirdscience>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.artifacer.weirdscience@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Weird Science</name>
					</weirdscience>
					<itemcreation>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.artifacer.itemcreation@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Item Creation</name>
					</itemcreation>
					<bonusfeats>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.artifacer.bonusfeats@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Bonus Feats</name>
					</bonusfeats>
					<salvage>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.artifacer.salvage@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Salvage</name>
					</salvage>
					<metamagicscience>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.artifacer.metamagicscience@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Metamagic Science</name>
					</metamagicscience>
					<improvedmetamagicscience>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.artifacer.improvedmetamagicscience@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Improved Metamagic Science</name>
					</improvedmetamagicscience>
					<improvedjackofalltrades>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.artifacer.improvedjackofalltrades@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Improved Jack of All Trades</name>
					</improvedjackofalltrades>
					<exemplar>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.artifacer.exemplar@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Exemplar</name>
					</exemplar>
				</index>
			</core>
		</artifacer>
		<cryptic>
			<basemenu>
				<name type="string">Cryptic Class</name>
				<index>
					<r1stats>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencetextwide</class>
							<recordname>lists.cryptic.statblock@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Leveling Stats</name>
					</r1stats>
					<r2proficiencies>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referenceindex</class>
							<recordname>lists.cryptic.proficiencies@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Proficiencies</name>
					</r2proficiencies>
					<r3corecryptic>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referenceindex</class>
							<recordname>lists.cryptic.core@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Core Cryptic</name>
					</r3corecryptic>
				</index>
			</basemenu>
			<statblock>
				<name type="string">cryptic</name>
				<text type="formattedtext">
					<p><b>Alignment:</b> Any</p>
					<p><b>Hit Die:</b> d8</p>
					<p><b>Class Skills</b></p>
					<p>The cryptic's class skills are Acrobatics (Dex), Appraise (Int), Autohypnosis* (Wis), Climb (Str), Craft (Int), Disable Device (Dex), Disguise (Cha), Escape Artist (Dex), Knowledge (all) (Int), Knowledge (psionics)* (Int), Linguistics (Int), Perception (Wis), Perform (Cha), Profession (Wis), Sense Motive (Wis), Sleight of Hand (Dex), Spellcraft (Int), Stealth (Dex), Swim (Str), and Use Magic Device (Cha).</p>
					<p><b>Skill Ranks Per Level:</b> 4 + Int modifier.</p>
					<p><b>Starting Wealth:</b> 3d6 x 10 gp (average 105 gp)</p>
					<table>
						<tr><td colspan="9"><b>Table: The Cryptic</b></td></tr>
						<tr decoration="underline"><td><b>Level </b></td><td colspan="2"><b>Base Attack</b></td><td><b>Fort</b></td><td><b>Ref</b></td><td><b>Will</b></td><td colspan="3"><b>Special</b></td></tr>
						<tr><td>1st</td><td colspan="2">+1</td><td>+2</td><td>+0</td><td>+2</td><td colspan="3">Altered defense 1, disrupt pattern 1d6, pattern designs, scribe tattoo, trapfinding, trapmaker</td></tr>
						<tr><td>2nd</td><td colspan="2">+2</td><td>+3</td><td>+0</td><td>+2</td><td colspan="3">Hidden pattern +2, insight</td></tr>
						<tr><td>3rd</td><td colspan="2">+3</td><td>+3</td><td>+1</td><td>+3</td><td colspan="3">Enhanced disruption +1d6, evasion</td></tr>
						<tr><td>4th</td><td colspan="2">+4</td><td>+4</td><td>+1</td><td>+4</td><td colspan="3">Insight, rapid defense</td></tr>
						<tr><td>5th</td><td colspan="2">+5</td><td>+4</td><td>+1</td><td>+4</td><td colspan="3">Altered defense 2, enhanced disruption +2d6, hidden pattern +4</td></tr>
						<tr><td>6th</td><td colspan="2">+6/+1</td><td>+5</td><td>+2</td><td>+5</td><td colspan="3">Insight, swift trapper</td></tr>
						<tr><td>7th</td><td colspan="2">+7/+2</td><td>+5</td><td>+2</td><td>+5</td><td colspan="3">Enhanced disruption +3d6</td></tr>
						<tr><td>8th</td><td colspan="2">+8/+3</td><td>+6</td><td>+2</td><td>+6</td><td colspan="3">Hidden pattern +6, insight</td></tr>
						<tr><td>9th</td><td colspan="2">+9/+4</td><td>+6</td><td>+3</td><td>+6</td><td colspan="3">Altered defense 3, enhanced disruption +4d6</td></tr>
						<tr><td>10th</td><td colspan="2">+10/+5</td><td>+7</td><td>+3</td><td>+7</td><td colspan="3">Hide in plain sight, insight</td></tr>
						<tr><td>11th</td><td colspan="2">+11/+6/+1</td><td>+7</td><td>+3</td><td>+7</td><td colspan="3">Enhanced disruption +5d6</td></tr>
						<tr><td>12th</td><td colspan="2">+12/+7/+2</td><td>+8</td><td>+4</td><td>+8</td><td colspan="3">Insight</td></tr>
						<tr><td>13th</td><td colspan="2">+13/+8/+3</td><td>+8</td><td>+4</td><td>+8</td><td colspan="3">Altered defense 4, enhanced disruption +6d6</td></tr>
						<tr><td>14th</td><td colspan="2">+14/+9/+4</td><td>+9</td><td>+4</td><td>+9</td><td colspan="3">Enduring defense, insight</td></tr>
						<tr><td>15th</td><td colspan="2">+15/+10/+5</td><td>+9</td><td>+5</td><td>+9</td><td colspan="3">Enhanced disruption +7d6</td></tr>
						<tr><td>16th</td><td colspan="2">+16/+11/+6/+1</td><td>+10</td><td>+5</td><td>+10</td><td colspan="3">Insight</td></tr>
						<tr><td>17th</td><td colspan="2">+17/+12/+7/+2</td><td>+10</td><td>+5</td><td>+10</td><td colspan="3">Altered defense 5, enhanced disruption +8d6</td></tr>
						<tr><td>18th</td><td colspan="2">+18/+13/+8/+3</td><td>+11</td><td>+6</td><td>+11</td><td colspan="3">Insight, unchanging pattern</td></tr>
						<tr><td>19th</td><td colspan="2">+19/+14/+9/+4</td><td>+11</td><td>+6</td><td>+11</td><td colspan="3">Enhanced disruption +9d6</td></tr>
						<tr><td>20th</td><td colspan="2">+20/+15/+10/+5</td><td>+12</td><td>+6</td><td>+12</td><td colspan="3">Supreme insight</td></tr>
					</table>
					<p></p>
					<table>
						<tr><td></td><td colspan="7"><b>Table: Customization/Power points per Day</b></td></tr>
						<tr decoration="underline"><td><b>Power Points/Day</b></td><td><b>Power Known</b></td><td><b>Maximum Design Level Known</b></td><td><b>Power Points/Day</b></td><td><b>Power Known</b></td><td><b>Maximum Design Level Known</b></td></tr>
						<tr><td>1st</td><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>1st</td><td>11th</td><td>36</td><td>11</td><td>4th</td></tr>
						<tr><td>2nd</td><td>2</td><td>2</td><td>1st</td><td>12th</td><td>44</td><td>12</td><td>4th</td></tr>
						<tr><td>3rd</td><td>4</td><td>3</td><td>1st</td><td>13th</td><td>52</td><td>13</td><td>5th</td></tr>
						<tr><td>4th</td><td>6</td><td>4</td><td>2nd</td><td>14th</td><td>60</td><td>14</td><td>5th</td></tr>
						<tr><td>5th</td><td>8</td><td>5</td><td>2nd</td><td>15th</td><td>68</td><td>15</td><td>5th</td></tr>
						<tr><td>6th</td><td>12</td><td>6</td><td>2nd</td><td>16th</td><td>80</td><td>16</td><td>6th</td></tr>
						<tr><td>7th</td><td>16</td><td>7</td><td>3rd</td><td>17th</td><td>92</td><td>17</td><td>6th</td></tr>
						<tr><td>8th</td><td>20</td><td>8</td><td>3rd</td><td>18th</td><td>104</td><td>18</td><td>6th</td></tr>
						<tr><td>9th</td><td>24</td><td>9</td><td>3rd</td><td>19th</td><td>116</td><td>19</td><td>6th</td></tr>
						<tr><td>10th</td><td>28</td><td>10</td><td>4th</td><td>20th</td><td>128</td><td>20</td><td>6th</td></tr>
					</table>
					<p></p>
					<p><h1><b>Class Features</b></h1></p>
					<p></p>
					<p>The following are class features of the cryptic.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p><b>Weapon and Armor Proficiencies</b></p>
					<p></p>
					<p>Cryptics are proficient with all simple, plus the rapier and shortbow. Cryptics are proficient with light armor but not with shields.</p>
					<p>Armor does not interfere with the cryptic's class features.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>Power Points/Day: A cryptic's ability to manifest powers is limited by the power points she has available. Her base daily allotment of power</p>
					<p>points is given on Table: The Cryptic. In addition, she receives bonus power points per day if she has a high Intelligence score</p>
					<p>(see Table: Ability Modifiers and Bonus Power Points). Her race may also provide bonus power points per day, as may certain feats and items.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p><b>Powers Known</b></p>
					<p></p>
					<p>A cryptic begins play knowing one cryptic power of your choice. Each time she achieves a new level, she unlocks the knowledge of a new power.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>Choose the powers known from the cryptic power list. (Exception: The feat Expanded Knowledge does allow a cryptic to learn powers from the</p>
					<p>lists of other classes.) A cryptic can manifest any power that has a power point cost equal to or lower than her manifester level.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>The total number of powers a cryptic can manifest in a day is limited only by her daily power points.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>A cryptic simply knows her powers; they are ingrained in her mind. She does not need to prepare them (in the way that some spellcasters</p>
					<p>prepare their spells), though she must get a good night's sleep each day to regain all her spent power points.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>The Difficulty Class for saving throws against cryptic powers is 10 + the power's level + the cryptic's Intelligence modifier.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p><b>Maximum Power Level Known</b></p>
					<p></p>
					<p>A cryptic begins play with the ability to learn 1st-level powers. As she attains higher levels, she may gain the ability to master more complex powers.</p>
					<p></p>
					<p>To learn or manifest a power, a cryptic must have an Intelligence score of at least 10 + the power's level.</p>
				</text>
			</statblock>
			<proficiencies>
				<name type="string">Proficiencies</name>
				<index>
					<simpleweapons>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.proficiencies.simpleweapons@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Simple Weapons</name>
					</simpleweapons>
					<lightarmor>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.proficiencies.lightarmor@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Light Armor</name>
					</lightarmor>
				</index>
			</proficiencies>
			<core>
				<name type="string">Core Cryptic</name>
				<index>
					<patterndesigns>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.cryptic.patterndesigns@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Pattern Designs</name>
					</patterndesigns>
					<altereddefense>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.cryptic.altereddefense@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Altered Defense</name>
					</altereddefense>
					<disruptpattern>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.cryptic.disruptpattern@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Disrupt Pattern</name>
					</disruptpattern>
					<lesserinsights>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.cryptic.lesserinsights@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Lesser Insights</name>
					</lesserinsights>
					<scribetattoo>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.cryptic.scribetattoo@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Scribe Tattoo</name>
					</scribetattoo>
					<trapfinding>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.cryptic.trapfinding@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Trap Finding</name>
					</trapfinding>
					<trapmaker>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.cryptic.trapmaker@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Trapmaker</name>
					</trapmaker>
					<hiddenpattern>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.cryptic.hiddenpattern@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Hidden Pattern</name>
					</hiddenpattern>
					<insight>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.cryptic.insight@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Insight</name>
					</insight>
					<enhanceddisruption>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.cryptic.enhanceddisruption@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Enhanced Disruption</name>
					</enhanceddisruption>
					<evasion>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.cryptic.evasion@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Evasion</name>
					</evasion>
					<rapiddefense>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.cryptic.rapiddefense@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Rapid Defense</name>
					</rapiddefense>
					<swifttrapper>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.cryptic.swifttrapper@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Swift Trapper</name>
					</swifttrapper>
					<enduringdefense>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.cryptic.enduringdefense@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Enduring Defense</name>
					</enduringdefense>
					<unchangingpattern>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.cryptic.unchangingpattern@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Unchanging Pattern</name>
					</unchangingpattern>
					<supremeinsight>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.cryptic.supremeinsight@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Supreme Insight</name>
					</supremeinsight>
				</index>
			</core>
		</cryptic>
		<tactician>
			<basemenu>
				<name type="string">tactician Class</name>
				<index>
					<r1stats>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencetextwide</class>
							<recordname>lists.tactician.statblock@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Leveling Stats</name>
					</r1stats>
					<r2proficiencies>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referenceindex</class>
							<recordname>lists.tactician.proficiencies@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Proficiencies</name>
					</r2proficiencies>
					<r3coretactician>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referenceindex</class>
							<recordname>lists.tactician.core@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Core tactician</name>
					</r3coretactician>
				</index>
			</basemenu>
			<statblock>
				<name type="string">tactician</name>
				<text type="formattedtext">
					<p><b>Alignment:</b> Any</p>
					<p><b>Hit Die:</b> d10</p>
					<p><b>Class Skills</b></p>
					<p>The aegis's class skills are Acrobatics (Dex), Autohypnosis* (Wis), Climb (Str), Craft (Int), Knowledge (psionics)* (Int), Profession (Wis), Spellcraft (Int), Swim (Str), and Use Magic Device (Cha).</p>
					<p><b>Skill Ranks Per Level:</b> 4 + Int modifier.</p>
					<p><b>Starting Wealth:</b> 3d6 x 10 gp (average 105 gp)</p>
					<table>
						<tr><td colspan="9"><b>Table: The aegis</b></td></tr>
						<tr decoration="underline"><td><b>Level </b></td><td colspan="2"><b>Base Attack</b></td><td><b>Fort</b></td><td><b>Ref</b></td><td><b>Will</b></td><td colspan="3"><b>Special</b></td></tr>
						<tr><td>1st</td><td colspan="2">+1</td><td>+2</td><td>+0</td><td>+2</td><td colspan="3">Astral repair, form astral suit</td></tr>
						<tr><td>2nd</td><td colspan="2">+2</td><td>+3</td><td>+0</td><td>+2</td><td colspan="3">Craftsman (+1), damage reduction (2/-)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>3rd</td><td colspan="2">+3</td><td>+3</td><td>+1</td><td>+3</td><td colspan="3">Invigorating suit, reconfigure (1/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>4th</td><td colspan="2">+4</td><td>+4</td><td>+1</td><td>+4</td><td colspan="3">Augment suit (1)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>5th</td><td colspan="2">+5</td><td>+4</td><td>+1</td><td>+4</td><td colspan="3">Damage reduction (3/-), Master Craftsman, reconfigure (2/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>6th</td><td colspan="2">+6/+1</td><td>+5</td><td>+2</td><td>+5</td><td colspan="3">Craftsman (+2)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>7th</td><td colspan="2">+7/+2</td><td>+5</td><td>+2</td><td>+5</td><td colspan="3">Reconfigure (3/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>8th</td><td colspan="2">+8/+3</td><td>+6</td><td>+2</td><td>+6</td><td colspan="3">Augment suit (2), damage reduction (4/-)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>9th</td><td colspan="2">+9/+4</td><td>+6</td><td>+3</td><td>+6</td><td colspan="3">Reconfigure (4/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>10th</td><td colspan="2">+10/+5</td><td>+7</td><td>+3</td><td>+7</td><td colspan="3">Craftsman (+3)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>11th</td><td colspan="2">+11/+6/+1</td><td>+7</td><td>+3</td><td>+7</td><td colspan="3">Damage reduction (5/-), reconfigure (5/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>12th</td><td colspan="2">+12/+7/+2</td><td>+8</td><td>+4</td><td>+8</td><td colspan="3">Augment suit (3), cannibalize suit (1/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>13th</td><td colspan="2">+13/+8/+3</td><td>+8</td><td>+4</td><td>+8</td><td colspan="3">Reconfigure (6/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>14th</td><td colspan="2">+14/+9/+4</td><td>+9</td><td>+4</td><td>+9</td><td colspan="3">Craftsman (+4), cannibalize suit (2/day), damage reduction (6/-)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>15th</td><td colspan="2">+15/+10/+5</td><td>+9</td><td>+5</td><td>+9</td><td colspan="3">Reconfigure (7/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>16th</td><td colspan="2">+16/+11/+6/+1</td><td>+10</td><td>+5</td><td>+10</td><td colspan="3">Augment suit (4), cannibalize suit (3/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>17th</td><td colspan="2">+17/+12/+7/+2</td><td>+10</td><td>+5</td><td>+10</td><td colspan="3">Damage reduction (7/-), reconfigure (8/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>18th</td><td colspan="2">+18/+13/+8/+3</td><td>+11</td><td>+6</td><td>+11</td><td colspan="3">Cannibalize suit (4/day), Craftsman (+5)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>19th</td><td colspan="2">+19/+14/+9/+4</td><td>+11</td><td>+6</td><td>+11</td><td colspan="3">Reconfigure (9/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>20th</td><td colspan="2">+20/+15/+10/+5</td><td>+12</td><td>+6</td><td>+12</td><td colspan="3">Augment suit (5), cannibalize suit (5/day), damage reduction (8/-), perfect merger</td></tr>
					</table>
					<p></p>
					<table>
						<tr><td></td><td colspan="7"><b>Table: Customization/Power points per Day</b></td></tr>
						<tr decoration="underline"><td><b>Lvl</b></td><td><b>Customization Points</b></td><td><b>Power Points/Day</b></td><td><b>Lvl</b></td><td><b>Customization Points</b></td><td><b>Power Points/Day</b></td></tr>
						<tr><td>1st</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>11th</td><td>15</td><td>24</td></tr>
						<tr><td>2nd</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>12th</td><td>16</td><td>28</td></tr>
						<tr><td>3rd</td><td>5</td><td>3</td><td>13th</td><td>17</td><td>32</td></tr>
						<tr><td>4th</td><td>7</td><td>5</td><td>14th</td><td>19</td><td>37</td></tr>
						<tr><td>5th</td><td>8</td><td>7</td><td>15th</td><td>20</td><td>42</td></tr>
						<tr><td>6th</td><td>9</td><td>9</td><td>16th</td><td>21</td><td>47</td></tr>
						<tr><td>7th</td><td>10</td><td>11</td><td>17th</td><td>22</td><td>52</td></tr>
						<tr><td>8th</td><td>11</td><td>14</td><td>18th</td><td>23</td><td>58</td></tr>
						<tr><td>9th</td><td>13</td><td>17</td><td>19th</td><td>25</td><td>64</td></tr>
						<tr><td>10th</td><td>14</td><td>20</td><td>20th</td><td>26</td><td>70</td></tr>
					</table>
				</text>
			</statblock>
			<proficiencies>
				<name type="string">Proficiencies</name>
				<index>
					<simpleweapons>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.proficiencies.simpleweapons@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Simple Weapons</name>
					</simpleweapons>
					<lightarmor>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.proficiencies.lightarmor@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Light Armor</name>
					</lightarmor>
				</index>
			</proficiencies>
			<core>
				<name type="string">Core tactician</name>
				<index>
					<astralrepair>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.tactician.astralrepair@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Astral Repair</name>
					</astralrepair>
				</index>
			</core>
		</tactician>
		<vitalist>
			<basemenu>
				<name type="string">Aegis Class</name>
				<index>
					<r1stats>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencetextwide</class>
							<recordname>lists.aegis.statblock@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Leveling Stats</name>
					</r1stats>
					<r2proficiencies>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referenceindex</class>
							<recordname>lists.aegis.proficiencies@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Proficiencies</name>
					</r2proficiencies>
					<r3favoredclass>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referenceindex</class>
							<recordname>lists.aegis.favoredclass@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Favored Class</name>
					</r3favoredclass>
					<r4coreaegis>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referenceindex</class>
							<recordname>lists.aegis.core@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Core aegis</name>
					</r4coreaegis>
					<!--				<r5aegisarchetypes>
					<listlink type="windowreference">
					<class>referenceindex</class>
					<recordname>lists.aegis.archetypes@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
					</listlink>
					<name type="string">Archetypes</name>
					</r5aegisarchetypes>-->
				</index>
			</basemenu>
			<statblock>
				<name type="string">aegis</name>
				<text type="formattedtext">
					<p><b>Alignment:</b> Any</p>
					<p><b>Hit Die:</b> d10</p>
					<p><b>Class Skills</b></p>
					<p>The aegis's class skills are Acrobatics (Dex), Autohypnosis* (Wis), Climb (Str), Craft (Int), Knowledge (psionics)* (Int), Profession (Wis), Spellcraft (Int), Swim (Str), and Use Magic Device (Cha).</p>
					<p><b>Skill Ranks Per Level:</b> 4 + Int modifier.</p>
					<p><b>Starting Wealth:</b> 3d6 x 10 gp (average 105 gp)</p>
					<table>
						<tr><td colspan="9"><b>Table: The aegis</b></td></tr>
						<tr decoration="underline"><td><b>Level </b></td><td colspan="2"><b>Base Attack</b></td><td><b>Fort</b></td><td><b>Ref</b></td><td><b>Will</b></td><td colspan="3"><b>Special</b></td></tr>
						<tr><td>1st</td><td colspan="2">+1</td><td>+2</td><td>+0</td><td>+2</td><td colspan="3">Astral repair, form astral suit</td></tr>
						<tr><td>2nd</td><td colspan="2">+2</td><td>+3</td><td>+0</td><td>+2</td><td colspan="3">Craftsman (+1), damage reduction (2/-)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>3rd</td><td colspan="2">+3</td><td>+3</td><td>+1</td><td>+3</td><td colspan="3">Invigorating suit, reconfigure (1/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>4th</td><td colspan="2">+4</td><td>+4</td><td>+1</td><td>+4</td><td colspan="3">Augment suit (1)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>5th</td><td colspan="2">+5</td><td>+4</td><td>+1</td><td>+4</td><td colspan="3">Damage reduction (3/-), Master Craftsman, reconfigure (2/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>6th</td><td colspan="2">+6/+1</td><td>+5</td><td>+2</td><td>+5</td><td colspan="3">Craftsman (+2)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>7th</td><td colspan="2">+7/+2</td><td>+5</td><td>+2</td><td>+5</td><td colspan="3">Reconfigure (3/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>8th</td><td colspan="2">+8/+3</td><td>+6</td><td>+2</td><td>+6</td><td colspan="3">Augment suit (2), damage reduction (4/-)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>9th</td><td colspan="2">+9/+4</td><td>+6</td><td>+3</td><td>+6</td><td colspan="3">Reconfigure (4/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>10th</td><td colspan="2">+10/+5</td><td>+7</td><td>+3</td><td>+7</td><td colspan="3">Craftsman (+3)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>11th</td><td colspan="2">+11/+6/+1</td><td>+7</td><td>+3</td><td>+7</td><td colspan="3">Damage reduction (5/-), reconfigure (5/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>12th</td><td colspan="2">+12/+7/+2</td><td>+8</td><td>+4</td><td>+8</td><td colspan="3">Augment suit (3), cannibalize suit (1/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>13th</td><td colspan="2">+13/+8/+3</td><td>+8</td><td>+4</td><td>+8</td><td colspan="3">Reconfigure (6/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>14th</td><td colspan="2">+14/+9/+4</td><td>+9</td><td>+4</td><td>+9</td><td colspan="3">Craftsman (+4), cannibalize suit (2/day), damage reduction (6/-)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>15th</td><td colspan="2">+15/+10/+5</td><td>+9</td><td>+5</td><td>+9</td><td colspan="3">Reconfigure (7/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>16th</td><td colspan="2">+16/+11/+6/+1</td><td>+10</td><td>+5</td><td>+10</td><td colspan="3">Augment suit (4), cannibalize suit (3/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>17th</td><td colspan="2">+17/+12/+7/+2</td><td>+10</td><td>+5</td><td>+10</td><td colspan="3">Damage reduction (7/-), reconfigure (8/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>18th</td><td colspan="2">+18/+13/+8/+3</td><td>+11</td><td>+6</td><td>+11</td><td colspan="3">Cannibalize suit (4/day), Craftsman (+5)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>19th</td><td colspan="2">+19/+14/+9/+4</td><td>+11</td><td>+6</td><td>+11</td><td colspan="3">Reconfigure (9/day)</td></tr>
						<tr><td>20th</td><td colspan="2">+20/+15/+10/+5</td><td>+12</td><td>+6</td><td>+12</td><td colspan="3">Augment suit (5), cannibalize suit (5/day), damage reduction (8/-), perfect merger</td></tr>
					</table>
					<p></p>
					<table>
						<tr><td></td><td colspan="7"><b>Table: Customization/Power points per Day</b></td></tr>
						<tr decoration="underline"><td><b>Lvl</b></td><td><b>Customization Points</b></td><td><b>Power Points/Day</b></td><td><b>Lvl</b></td><td><b>Customization Points</b></td><td><b>Power Points/Day</b></td></tr>
						<tr><td>1st</td><td>3</td><td>1</td><td>11th</td><td>15</td><td>24</td></tr>
						<tr><td>2nd</td><td>4</td><td>2</td><td>12th</td><td>16</td><td>28</td></tr>
						<tr><td>3rd</td><td>5</td><td>3</td><td>13th</td><td>17</td><td>32</td></tr>
						<tr><td>4th</td><td>7</td><td>5</td><td>14th</td><td>19</td><td>37</td></tr>
						<tr><td>5th</td><td>8</td><td>7</td><td>15th</td><td>20</td><td>42</td></tr>
						<tr><td>6th</td><td>9</td><td>9</td><td>16th</td><td>21</td><td>47</td></tr>
						<tr><td>7th</td><td>10</td><td>11</td><td>17th</td><td>22</td><td>52</td></tr>
						<tr><td>8th</td><td>11</td><td>14</td><td>18th</td><td>23</td><td>58</td></tr>
						<tr><td>9th</td><td>13</td><td>17</td><td>19th</td><td>25</td><td>64</td></tr>
						<tr><td>10th</td><td>14</td><td>20</td><td>20th</td><td>26</td><td>70</td></tr>
					</table>
				</text>
			</statblock>
			<proficiencies>
				<name type="string">Proficiencies</name>
				<index>
					<simpleweapons>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.proficiencies.simpleweapons@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Simple Weapons</name>
					</simpleweapons>
					<lightarmor>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.proficiencies.lightarmor@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Light Armor</name>
					</lightarmor>
				</index>
			</proficiencies>
			<core>
				<name type="string">Core Aegis</name>
				<index>
					<astralrepair>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.aegis.astralrepair@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Astral Repair</name>
					</astralrepair>
					<formastralsuit>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.aegis.formastralsuit@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Form Astral Suit</name>
					</formastralsuit>
					<craftsman>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.aegis.craftsman@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Craftsman</name>
					</craftsman>
					<damagereduction>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.aegis.damagereduction@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Damage Reduction</name>
					</damagereduction>
					<invigoratingsuit>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.aegis.invigoratingsuit@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Invigorating Suit</name>
					</invigoratingsuit>
					<reconfigure>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.aegis.reconfigure@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Reconfigure</name>
					</reconfigure>
					<augmentsuit>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.aegis.augmentsuit@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Augment Suit</name>
					</augmentsuit>
					<mastercraftsman>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.aegis.mastercraftsman@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Master Craftsman</name>
					</mastercraftsman>
					<cannibalizesuit>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.aegis.cannibalizesuit@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Cannibalize Suit</name>
					</cannibalizesuit>
					<perfectmerger>
						<listlink type="windowreference">
							<class>referencefeat</class>
							<recordname>reference.aegis.perfectmerger@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
						</listlink>
						<name type="string">Perfect Merger</name>
					</perfectmerger>
				</index>
			</core>
		</vitalist>
		
	</lists>
		<item>
			<librarylink type="windowreference">
				<class>referenceindexsorted</class>
				<recordname>lists.item@PFRPG Misc Classes</recordname>
			</librarylink>
			<name type="string">Items</name>
		</item>
</root>
